Kai Roberts

Newcastle upon Tyne - NE51SF

07772479485 | kai roberts@icloud.com | www.linkedin.com/in/kai-roberts/

Portfolio: www.kairoberts.dev

ITIL 4 Certified Computer Science Graduate with a passion for technology, always aiming to improve my skill set and priding myself on working hard to achieve what I want from life. I possess knowledge in Cyber Security, Networking, Programming, Web Development and SQL. I have excellent written and verbal communication and have worked numerous customer-based roles as well as experience in Service Delivery.

Education

BSc (Hons) Computer Science (2:1 - 68%), York St. John University 2017 - 2020

- Dissertation title: An investigation into whether force sensitive resistors can improve the accuracy of landed punches within boxing (Grade 2:1).
- Technical understanding of Cyber Security shown through Cybercrime Security module in which I learned how to execute attacks on TCP, reverse shell hijackings, create my own VPN, bypass firewalls and run DNS attacks, whilst packet sniffing through Wireshark. All carried out locally between two virtual machines using Kali Linux terminals. (Grade 1st).
- Strong understanding in computer networks shown through a networking module where I learned such things as TCP/IP, DNS, UDP, DHCP, Switches, Routers, Firewalls, WAN, MAN, LAN, PAN and more (Grade 2:2).
- Strong foundation within the Internet of Things (IoT), where I programmed a light sensitive motor in Arduino to open and close bedroom curtains depending on the level of light in the room (Grade 2:1). In depth understanding of HTML and CSS along with fundamentals in Python Flask and JavaScript. My final year
- Advanced Web Development project was aimed around personal training during a pandemic (Grade 2:1).
- Ability to effectively mock-up then implement Database design through phpMyAdmin and MySQL (Grade 2:1).
- Core knowledge of programming in Java, achieving grades of 2:1 and 1St in these modules.

Walbottle Campus, Newcastle Upon Tyne 2009 - 2016

- A Levels: IT (Triple Distinction*) English Language (B)
- GCSEs: 1 B, 6 C's, 1 D (Including English B, Maths and Science C)

Employment History:

Tier One Support Analyst - C&C Group (1 Year 7 Months - Current Role - Fully Remote) **Newcastle upon Tyne**

- ITIL4 Certified
- Can demonstrate a wide range of abilities across different areas such as trouble-shooting hardware and software, data uploads, data fixes, technical support, password resets and system usage support across multiple pieces of software.
- Performing daily checks across multiple servers and web applications every morning and evening by checking log files, running SQL queries, checking scheduled tasks, creating reports and also emailing teams when things weren't working
- Helping nurses over the phone to diagnose issues with their computers, such as, checking cables are correct, remoting into the computer to help uncover the issue, checking the IP address configurations, reading error logs, installing or updating Antivirus software, downloading MSI's to update firewall rules and getting in touch with local IT when needing to have them whitelist IP addresses.
- Document each ticket clearly and concisely as well as tracking them to allow faster resolution times.
- Be the first point of contact for all incoming requests by email and phone and to accurately triage each ticket to the correct team.
- Providing customers with confirmation emails to let them know their issue is being dealt with.
- Creating easy to follow documents for other team members to use and learn from when nothing existed prior.
- Training and developing new starters to where they can work independently without fault.
- Working within a timeframe to make sure SLAs were not breached.
- Using SQL to extract data needed to update daily, weekly and monthly reports with the latest business figures for the management team.
- Importing data provided by clients each month.

Food delivery rider - Deliveroo York

Sept 2019 - April 2021

- Strong work ethic and self-discipline shown through self-employment and having the ability to choose own working
- Ability to meet daily targets set by myself in order to make enough earnings to cover the rent for my student accommodation.
- Excellent communication skills used when customers are not happy with their orders, knowing the protocol to follow to resolve the issue.
- Competent at making delivery schedules on time.

Barista/Waiter/Bartender - Principal Hotel

Jan 2018 - Feb 2019 York

- Worked under high pressure situations which involved a high degree of multitasking when the restaurant was at full capacity.
- A trustworthy employee granted the responsibility of opening and closing the tills.
- Flexibility shown on several occasions when asked to stay later or start earlier to help out.
- Confident in controlling the room alone on days when other employees did not show up through illness.
- Adaptability shown when asked by management to move onto the bar during busy periods.
- Ability to memorise information, such as dinner and drinks menus, or room directions for guests.

Telemarketer - Utilita

Oct 2016 - Apr 2017

Newcastle upon Tyne

- Learned to build up rapport with customers over the telephone in order to achieve sales.
- Objection handling through deep product knowledge to reduce any potential loss of sales.
- Ability to actively listen to customers gueries regarding the product in order to keep hang up percentages low.

Market Researcher - Populus Data Solutions

May 2014 - Oct 2016

- **Newcastle upon Tyne**
 - Learned how to effectively communicate with people over the phone in order to fulfil targets.
 - Reliable as I had to handle private information regarding the caller.
 - Strong analytical ability shown through remembering everything the customer spoke about to type out after.

Online Courses

The Creative React and Redux Course – Dev Ed React Front to Back Course – Brad Traversy

Achievements

- ITIL4 Certified (Certificate available on request).
- Certified PoCBA (Point of Care Blood Analyser) Nurse.
- Awarded free Deliveroo kit worth £50 for being in York's top 1% of riders.
- Awarded a hamper at the Principal Hotel for managing the room alone when staff called in sick.

Interests

Cyber Security, Mixed Martial Arts, Cycling, Running, Strength Training, Cooking and F1

References

Available upon request.